OK so we've talked about the.
好的，我们已经讨论过了。
That's a dog barking outside.
那是一只狗在外面狂吠。
We've talked about the past progressive tense where something is going on.
我们已经讨论过发生某事的过去进行时态。
And we talked about the simple past.
我们谈到了简单的过去。
Pretty simple pretty easy.
很简单很容易。
Now it starts to get a little bit more complicated.
现在它开始变得有点复杂了。
We're going to talk about present perfect OK.
我们将谈论现在完美的OK。
I'm going to try to draw it out so you can get a picture of why we would use this.
我将尝试将其绘制出来，以便您了解我们为什么要使用它。
And then we'll of course look at some examples.
然后我们当然会看一些例子。
This is a bit tough because of when we use it.
这有点困难，因为我们使用它的时候。
And it's also a little bit tough because how you make it is more than just changing one word.
而且它也有点难，因为你如何制作它不仅仅是改变一个词。
Usually the present perfect focuses on something that we say now about the past as well.
通常现在完成时也关注我们现在所说的关于过去的事情。
It includes the past and the present.
它包括过去和现在。
The first one that we use is to express something that we do now or is still going on now but which
我们使用的第一个是表达我们现在正在做或仍在进行的事情，但是
began before.
之前就开始了。
And we're sort of combining the fact that it began before and has continued up to the present moment.
我们在某种程度上结合了它之前开始并一直持续到现在的事实。
So all the way up until now to do that we use have or has and then we use the what's called the past
所以一直到现在我们使用 have 或 has 然后我们使用所谓的过去
participle the past participle is a special verb.
分词 过去分词是特殊动词。
OK.
好的。
It's a special verb because it's sometimes different than the simple past.
这是一个特殊的动词，因为它有时与过去时不同。
For example you know go and you know went right went is the simple past But gone is the past participle
例如you know go and you know going right going 是过去式，但 gone 是过去分词
Gone is the past participle so have gone would be the correct way to use it OK have gone and there are
Gone 是过去分词，所以 have gone 是正确的使用方式 OK have gone and there are
lots of different past participles.
很多不同的过去分词。
The difficult thing is that sometimes they're different from the simple past and sometimes they're the
困难的是，有时它们与简单的过去不同，有时它们是
same.
相同的。
For example we talked about the word walk before have walked is also the past participle WRAL K D.
比如我们讲过的单词walk before have walk也是过去分词WRAL K D。
I walked I have walked it's the same but for this one go went and gone it's different.
我走了我走过它是一样的，但对于这一次去去去它是不同的。
And you just have to get a feeling for it or if you really want to get serious you can look up a long
你只需要对它有一种感觉，或者如果你真的想认真起来，你可以查很久
list of verbs and study what the past participles are.
动词列表并研究过去分词是什么。
I would recommend just reading and watching movies and talking to people to get a feeling for which
我建议只是阅读和看电影并与人们交谈以了解其中
ones they are and I think you probably know many of them now you would have also seen another form where
他们是，我想你现在可能知道其中很多，你也会看到另一种形式
you have have has right.
你有权利。
I have.
我有。
She has.
她有。
It has.
它有。
They have.
他们有。
Then you have the past participle bin b e n.
然后你有过去分词bin be n。
Yes.
是的。
Yes bin.
是的斌。
It's got to be bin.
应该是bin
OK.
好的。
B was or were and the past participle is been I have been.
B was or were，过去分词是 be I have been。
She has been it has been they have been and then a verb like this plus i n g OK for example she have
She has been it has been they have been 然后像这样的动词加上 i n g OK 例如她有
or has has been living i n g living she has been eating she has been going she has been talking whatever
或者一直在生活 她一直在吃 她一直在走 她一直在说什么
she's been talking for forty five minutes
她已经讲了四十五分钟了
when will she finish.
她什么时候完成。
That means she's still talking now he's been walking for a week he's been walking for a week that means
这意味着她现在还在说话 他已经走了一周 他已经走了一周 这意味着
he's doing it still and it started a week ago this is how we usually use this kind of grammar this kind
他还在做它一周前就开始了这就是我们通常使用这种语法的方式
of tense.
的紧张。
OK something that started before and continues now.
好的，以前开始，现在继续。
So we'll look at some examples of how we do that and then we'll talk about this next kind which is a
所以我们将看一些我们如何做到这一点的例子，然后我们将讨论下一种
little bit more it's a little bit more complicated.
多一点它有点复杂。
OK.
好的。
So this type I I have been playing football for three years.
所以这种类型的我已经踢了三年足球了。
Does that mean that I'm playing football at this moment.
这是否意味着我此时正在踢足球。
No.
不。
That means in my life.
这意味着在我的生活中。
Right.
正确的。
I started three years ago and I still play maybe I only play once a week or once a month.
我三年前就开始玩了，我现在还在玩，也许我每周只玩一次，或者每个月玩一次。
But the point is it's still going on now for me.
但关键是它现在对我来说仍在继续。
OK.
好的。
I have been playing football for three years continuing.
我一直在踢足球三年。
Let's try another one.
让我们尝试另一个。
I've.
我有。
We can also say I've I've means I have.
我们也可以说我有我已经意味着我有。
Right.
正确的。
I've been working overtime a lot recently now for this one.
我最近一直在为这个加班很多。
We don't say how much time has passed and that's OK.
我们没有说已经过去了多少时间，这没关系。
The point is that it did begin before some point maybe a week or two weeks or three weeks we don't know
关键是它确实在我们不知道的某个时间点之前开始了，可能是一周、两周或三周
exactly but it's still going on now.
确切地说，但它现在仍在继续。
That's the important point.
这是重要的一点。
OK.
好的。
So something started before continuing now.
所以在继续之前开始了一些事情。
I have been working overtime a lot recently working overtime by the way means that you go over 40 hours
我一直在加班很多最近加班顺便说一下你超过40小时
in a workweek usually.
通常在一个工作周内。
So usually supposed to work eight hours a day maybe you work 10 hours every day.
所以通常应该每天工作 8 小时，也许你每天工作 10 小时。
It's called overtime.
这叫加班。
It's called overtime and working overtime a lot recently.
最近很多都叫加班和加班。
So this one is kind of simple right.
所以这个很简单。
Now the other way that we use this kind of tense is to talk about something that's about the past.
现在我们使用这种时态的另一种方式是谈论关于过去的事情。
It's true about the past but we're saying that it's it's true now about the past that that might be
过去是真实的，但我们是说现在关于过去的真实，那可能是
a little bit confusing right.
有点混乱吧。
But if I give you a couple of examples I think you get the idea a little bit better.
但如果我给你举几个例子，我想你会更好地理解这个想法。
So this one we usually don't say have been blah blah blah.
所以这个我们通常不说是废话。
We just say I have done that.
我们只是说我已经做到了。
We just use the have and then past participle for example I have visited Canada three times totally
我们只使用 have 和过去分词，例如我总共访问过加拿大 3 次
in my life.
在我生命中。
Now why wouldn't I just say I went to Canada three times.
现在我为什么不直接说我去过加拿大三次。
What's the difference between I have been to Canada three times and I went to Canada three times.
我去过加拿大 3 次和去过加拿大 3 次有什么区别。
When we're talking about how many times we've done something totally right or within a certain time
当我们谈论有多少次我们完全正确或在特定时间内完成某事时
period we could say I have been to Canada I have visited Canada.
期间我们可以说我去过加拿大我去过加拿大。
Totally right or within one year or whatever three times and we don't care about when each time happened.
完全正确或在一年内或任何三次，我们不在乎每次发生的时间。
So then we use this one.
那么我们就用这个。
That's how we use it.
这就是我们使用它的方式。
That's true now about the past.
现在关于过去也是如此。
If I want to say when I went then I'll use the simple past.
如果我想说我什么时候去的，那么我会用简单的过去。
I've been to Canada three times I went last June and I went twice the year before.
去年六月我去过加拿大三次，前一年去了两次。
So we often use the simple past to talk about the specific times and or when it happened and we use
所以我们经常用简单的过去来谈论具体的时间和或发生的时间，我们用
this one to just say totally this many times don't worry about the details we're not going to focus
这个只是说这么多次不用担心我们不会关注的细节
on the details.
关于细节。
We're just talking about right now at this point in my life.
我们现在只是在谈论我生命中的这一点。
How many times has this thing happened or has it happened or not.
这件事发生了多少次或发生过或没有发生过。
Sometimes when we want to say did it happen or not.
有时当我们想说它发生与否时。
We used the same way we can say for example I have seen you before seen as the past participle of Si
我们使用的方式与我们可以说的方式相同，例如 I've seen you before seen 作为 Si 的过去分词
I have seen you before.
我以前见过你。
It's true.
这是真的。
You don't you say I saw you before because then we might focus on the details.
你不说我以前见过你，因为那样我们可能会专注于细节。
I saw you before last Tuesday I saw you last week.
我在上周二之前见过你 我上周见过你。
The details.
细节。
Right.
正确的。
But if we say I have seen you before we don't care about when it happened.
但如果我们说我之前见过你，我们不在乎它是什么时候发生的。
It's just true.
这是真的。
Right.
正确的。
So we use this one often when we're talking about just the reality the truth.
所以我们在谈论的时候经常使用这个现实真相。
If we wanted to say the opposite.
如果我们想说相反的话。
I have never seen you before is also correct.
我以前从未见过你也是正确的。
We can add the word never here.
我们可以在此处添加“从不”一词。
I've never seen you before.
我以前从没见过你。
It is not true that I have seen you but sometimes it really is exactly the same as the simple past tense.
我见过你不是真的，但有时它确实与简单过去时完全一样。
And you can choose either one it doesn't really matter.
你可以选择其中任何一个，这并不重要。
You can say I already eight it happen.
你可以说我已经八了。
You're done.
你完成了。
OK.
好的。
I have already.
我已经。
What should I put here.
我应该在这里放什么。
What's the past participle for eight eaten.
八吃的过去分词是什么
I have already eaten I already ate.
我已经吃过了我已经吃过了。
Is it different.
是不是不一样。
Not really.
并不真地。
So sometimes they're kind of the same and you can choose either one but in many cases many times they
所以有时它们是一样的，你可以选择其中之一，但在很多情况下，它们
are not the same.
不一样。
And you need to be careful if you want to talk about details maybe use simple past if you want to talk
如果你想谈论细节，你需要小心如果你想谈论，可以使用简单过去
about totally how many times or totally did it happen or not.
大约发生了多少次或完全发生或没有发生。
Is it true then maybe use the present perfect tense.
是真的那么也许使用现在完成时。